Robert H. Taylor Collection of English and American Literature, 1280s-1958 (bulk 1800s-1930s ): Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
- Series 3: Modern Manuscripts (Unbound) and Correspondence, 1545-1969; 23 archival boxes
  - Thackeray, William Makepeace, 1811-1863, 1841-1893; 5 folders
    - 17 letters 1841-1893: 1 to James Russell Lowell, 1 to Anthony Trollope (signature clipped), 1 to Ebenezer Landells, 1 to "Madam" [Anne Marsh-Caldwell] with faint pen-and-ink sketches on verso (by WMT?), 1 to "My dear West" (with drawing), 1 to "My dear Bullar," 1 to "My dear Evans," 1 to Messrs. Chapman & Hall, 1 to Mr. "G.(?) Williams, 1 to "Doctor Halliday," 1 to John Lewis Merivale (addressed J.L.M.), 4 to unidentified persons, 1 by Eyre Crowe to F. G. Waugh about a visit of Thackeray to the Atheneum Club, 1 illustrated letter to Frederick Walker, 1 folder
      - verse, poem in Latin (on verso of verse letter to Lucy Baxter), 1841 which first appeared in Frazer's Magazine in June, 1841, portion of 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 25)
      - prose, two leaves of "The Four Georges," undated numbered 17 & 19, portion of 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 25)
      - verse, "I am just from Hanway Court...," undated 48 lines, with small drawing and envelope addressed to "Mr. C. Collins", portion of 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 25)
      - pen-and-ink drawing, a turbaned sultan with sword and a young girl with jug, "Done at Cattermole's...", undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 25)
      - comic drawing, "George the Fourth - at Virginia Water," with note by Edward Fitzgerald naming Thackeray as the artist and providing the title, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 25)
      - pen-and-ink drawing, "A Good Coat," with note by Edward Fitzgerald naming Thackeray as the artist and providing the title, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Autograph letters and manuscripts, 1842-1863; 1 folder
      - 12 letters 1842-1863 1 to William Harrison Ainsworth, 1 to Charles Dickens, 2 to James Fraser, 1 to A. Hayward, 1 to [William Charles] Macready, 1 to [John] Murray, 1 to "My dearest Minnikin" (daughter Harriet), 1 by John Forster to John Taylor (copy by WMT), 1 by Forster to Thackeray and 1 (copy) by Thackeray in reply; 1 letter (in French) by Francis Seymour-Conway, Marquis of Hertford, to "Madame" about Thackeray, portion of 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 26)
      - portion of the Roundabout Papers, undated 1 p. (numbered "3"), portion of 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 26)
      - one leaf of the plan for The Newcomes, chapters XVI-XXIV, with small pen-and-ink drawing, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 26)
      - holograph manuscript leaf from the end of Chapter 79 of The Virginians, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - Autograph letters and misc., undated; 1 folder
      - Includes 11 letters and notes by Thackeray to various members of the Ford and Molesworth families, mostly undated, with a carte de visite of Thackeray, two letters (1856-1861) from his daughter Anne (1 to "My dear Lady Molesworth," 1 to "Dear Mrs. Ford), and news clippings about Thackeray's death and funeral, 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - Blue Beard, 1849; 1 folder
      - "Bluebeard & Butts at a breakfast table. Talbot waiting," circa 1849 9 pp., fragment of an unfinished play in blank verse with 2 letters by Hester Thackeray Ritchie (granddaughter) about it, 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - The Knights of Borsellen, undated; 1 folder
      - fragment of The Knights of Borsellen, undated 3 pp., an unfinished account of the rising of citizens of Liege against their bishop, portion of 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 29)
      - fragment of The Knights of Borsellen, undated 1 p., an abandoned attempt at the opening paragraph of the novel, written in the 1st person, portion of 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Thompson, Francis, 1859-1907, undated; 1 folder
    - Any Saint, undated; 1 folder
      - verse manuscript, undated 11 pp., a working draft with revisions, 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Thomson, James, 1834-1882, undated; 1 folder
    - The Deliverer, undated; 1 folder
      - verse manuscript, 47 stanzas, 8 pp., with note "Saty. 18/8/60 Mondy. 12/11/60", undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Thomson, James, 1700-1748, 1735-1748; 1 folder
    - Three autograph letters, 1735-1748; 1 folder
      - 3 letters circa 1735-1748 1 to his sister Jean, 1 to "Mr. Paterson," 1 to unidentified person, 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Thoreau, Henry David, 1817-1862, 1835 October 2-1860; 3 folders
    - 2 letters 1838-1847: 1 to D. G. Haskins, 1 (initialed) to Ralph Waldo Emerson; 1 leaf from Thoreau'"Autumnal Tints" (printers copy sent to the Atlantic Monthly in 1862), 1835 October 2-16; 1 folder
      - draft of part of Week on the Merrimac, beginning "There is an infidelity...," undated 1 p.; on verso is part of a school exercise described below, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 33)
      - part of a school class exercise, beginning "...find another, perhaps no better satisfied...," 1 p., [Theme no. 22, 1835 October 2-16]; on verso is part of the manuscript described above, portion of 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 33)
      - "I have seen some insolent Connecticut/...," undated 13 lines, 1 p. (Box 19, Folder 33)
      - carte de visite of Thoreau, from the Dunshee ambrotype, the last photograph of Thoreau taken before his death, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - Autograph letters and manuscripts, 1840-1860; 1 folder
      - 4 letters 1840-1860: 1 to Charles S. Wheeler, 1 to "Mr. Blake," 1 to E. H. Russell, 1 to Sophia Thoreau, portion of 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 34)
      - prose, part of a draft of Cape Cod, undated; 1 p. (Box 19, Folder 34)
      - prose, parts of Thoreau's Journal, covering, 1852 June 21-30; 8 pp. (Box 19, Folder 34)
      - verse, "The Soul's Season," beginning "Thank God who seasons thus the year/...," undated 9 stanzas, 2 pp., with holograph revisions, portion of 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - "The Moon", undated; 1 folder
      - ["Moonlight"], lecture delivered in Plymouth, Mass., in 1854, 6 pp., undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - Tickell, Richard, 1751-1793, undated; 1 folder
    - 2 letters; "Epistle from the Hon'ble C. Fox, Partridge-Shooting to the Hon'ble J. Townshend," manuscript of verse with some corrections, 7 pp., circa 1779 [see: Combe, William, 1742-1823 folder for the related poem and response by Combe], undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - Tickell, Thomas, 1686-1740, 1736; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to John Boyle, Earl of Orrery, 1736; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - Tinker, Chauncey Brewster, 1876-1963, 1954; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to Michael Papantonio, 1954; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - Tollet, W., undated; 1 folder
    - pamphlet volume of original, unpublished poems, entitled "Columen Literarum. The Third Essay of the Belles Lettres by W.T.," "London: Designed for a M.S. 1710," 28 pp, bound in Dutch decorated paper covers, attributed to Tollet by Percy Dobell, undated; 1 folder (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - Trollope, Anthony, 1815-1882, 1846-1946; 23 folders
    - 4 letters 1860-1882]: 1 to Baron [Bernhard] von Tauchnitz, 1 to Charles Merivale (includes 1 letter by Frances Milton Trollope to Harriet Fisher mounted on same sheet), 1 to "My dear Latran"(?), 1 to unidentified person, 1 folder
      - 2 pages (1 leaf) from Working Notebook, noting dates and number of pages written on his Memoirs; begins 1 January 1876 and ends 13 April 1876, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Garrick Club certificate of life membership for Trollope, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Letters I, 1867-1875; 1 folder
      - 6 letters 1867-1875: 1 to Alfred Austin, 5 to unidentified persons, plus 1 signed card, 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Letters II, undated; 1 folder
      - 10 letters (1835-1882) to Richard Bentley, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Letters III, 1867-1879; 1 folder
      - 6 letters 1867-1879: 4 (1 incomplete) to John Blackwood, 2 to "My dear Burney", 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Letters IV, 1856-1881; 1 folder
      - 7 letters 1856-1881: 2 to Frederic Chapman, 1 to Charles Dickens, 1 to [Alfred] Elmore, 1 to "Miss Dulaney"(?), 1 to "My dear Kate," 1 to unidentified person, 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Letters V, 1859-1881; 1 folder
      - 6 letters 1859-1881: 2 to [Thomas] Grattan, 1 to Henry Howard, 1 to John Humbly, 1 to "Mr. Joyce," 1 to unidentified person, 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Letters VI, 1865-1878; 1 folder
      - 9 letters 1865-1878: 3 to [Charles] Lever, 1 to "My dear Lewes," 1 to "My dear Macleod,' 1 to [George] Meredith, 1 to "Mr. Merivale," 1 to [Cecilia Meetkerke] (with photograph of Trollope pasted on), 1 to "My dear Friend", 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Letters VII, 1860-1878; 1 folder
      - 7 letters 1860-1878: 1 to "My dear Pollock," 3 to [Charles] Reade, 2 to William Howard Russell, 1 to "Mr. Smith", 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Letters VIII, 1864-1878; 1 folder
      - 3 letters 1864-1878: 1 to Miss Taylor," 1 to "My dear John," 1 to "Miss Tiedemann" (in third person), 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Letters IX.1 - to Harry Trollope, 1877; 15 letters (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Letters IX.2 - to Harry Trollope, 1879; 3 letters (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Letters IX.3 - to Harry Trollope, 1880; 16 letters (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Letters IX.4 - to Harry Trollope, 1881; 24 letters (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Letters IX.5 - to Harry Trollope, 1882; 21 letters) = 79 total (80 in MASC (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Letters X - to the Trollope family and others, 1854-1882; 1 folder
      - 9 letters 1854-1882: 1 to "Tom" [Thomas Adolphus Trollope], 5 to "Dearest Love," 1 to "Dearest Madame" 1 to "Dearest Mother," 1 to "Lady Tulloch"(?), 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Letters to John Lewis Merivale, 1848-1862; 1 folder
      - Autograph note by Janet Louisa [?], daughter of John Lewis Merivale, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 16)
      - 30 autograph letters signed to John Lewis Merivale ( undated, 1848-1857, 1862), including 2 incomplete [lacking first and last pages, respectively] and a carte-de-visite photograph of Trollope, portion of 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - "Young Cincinnatus", 1846; 1 folder
      - Autograph letter signed to [Unknown], 1846; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Letters to Anthony Trollope, 1851-1879; 1 folder
      - 27 letters 1851-1879: 1 by George Bartley, 1 by Shirley Brooks, 1 by Robert Browning, 1 by Lord George Carlisle, 1 by John Forster, 3 by J. A. Froude, 2 (1 in third person) by Alexander Kinglake, 2 by Edwin Landseer, 1 by Henry Wadsworth Longfellow, 2 by E. Bulwer Lytton, 1 by Cardinal Henry Manning, 2 by J. Everett Millais, 6 by Richard Monckton Milnes, Baron Houghton (5 are signed "Houghton"), 1 by Samuel Warren, 2 by unidentified persons including pen-and-ink sketches, portion of 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 18)
      - 6 letters (1873-1876) to Mrs. Rose Trollope: 1 by Anne Thackeray (Ritchie), 2 by Robert Browning, 3 by Mrs. [Margaret] Oliphant, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Letters about Anthony Trollope, 1861-1946; 1 folder
      - 2 letters 1861-1946: 1 by James Ross to unidentified person, 1 to [Robert H.] Taylor by Bradford Booth, 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Notes on Chapter XI (pp. 171-183) of "South Africa" (abridged from the 4th ed., 1879) by Bartle Frere, 1880; 105 pp.
      - 1 letter by Frere to Anthony Trollope, 1880; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Letter on South Africa, 1877; 1 folder
      - 3 letters (1875-1877) by Anthony Trollope to Nicholas Trubner, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 21)
      - memorandum of agreement between Trollope and Nicholas Trubner, regarding series of 15 letters Trollope will write for him as a traveler in South Africa, 1877; portion of 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 21)
      - "Letter 1 -- South Africa as a Dutch Possession," 9 pp., first letter of the series for Trubner, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Galleys for Framley Parsonage - Chapters VII-IX, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Map of Barsetshire, undated; 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Trollope, Frances, 1780-1863, 1834-1856; more than 4 folders
    - I.1 verse, "Daffodil," undated six stanzas, 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - I.2 25 letters 1834-1856: 7 to her son Anthony Trollope (including 1 fragment and 2 which contain notes (initialed) by Anthony's brother, Thomas Adolphus Trollope, with at least one addressed to both Anthony and Rose Trollope, "dear children"), 4 to Rose Trollope, 1 to her grandson Henry Merivale Trollope, 1 to [her daughter Mrs. Tilley], 1 to "Miss Herbert," 1 to [Julia Pertz, wife of G.H.P.], 4 to Moritz Count Dietrichstein, 6 to unidentified persons, 1 folder (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - II.1-6 Letters to Richard Bentley, undated; more than 1 folder
      - 32 letters (1830-1843) in 6 folders, undated; 6 folders (Box 20, Folder 26-31)
    - III.1-5 Letters to T. A. Trollope in 5 folders, undated; more than 1 folder
      - 23 letters (1808-1810) to her [future] husband, Thomas Anthony Trollope, undated; 5 folders (Box 20, Folder 32-36)
  - Trollope, Henry, 1756-1839, 1832; 1 folder
    - 5 letters to "My dear mother" [Frances Trollope], 1832; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Trollope, Henry Merivale, 1846-1926, undated; 2 folders
    - Correspondence I, undated; 1 folder
      - 3 letters (1883-85?) (retained copies) to William Blackwood III, undated; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence II, undated; 1 folder
      - 22 letters (1883-1885) by William Blackwood III, undated; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Trollope, T. Adolphus, 1810-1892, 1872-1891; 3 folders
    - Autograph letter (fragment) to "My dear Hill", 1891; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Autograph letters to Mr. and Mrs. Hiram Powers, 1872-1873; 1 folder
      - 2 letters to Hiram Powers (, ), 1872; portion of 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - 1 letter to Mrs. Powers, on the occasion of her husband's death, 1873; portion of 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Autograph letters of T. Adolphus and Frances Eleanor Trollope, undated; 1 folder
      - 59 letters (1838-1892) by Thomas Adolphus: 8 to Richard Bentley, 51 (1 on 3/12/1873 letter by Frances Eleanor Trollope) to George Bentley, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - 19 letters (1872-1897) by Frances Eleanor Trollope: 16 (1 with note by Thomas Adolphus Trollope) to George Bentley, 1 (1872) addressed to Richard Bentley (but he died in 1871), 2 (1897) to another Bentley (George died in 1895), undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Trollope, Thomas Anthony, d. 1835, 1836; 2 folders
    - 20 letters (1808-1810) to his future wife, Frances Milton, undated; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - certificate of burial, 1836; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Twain, Mark, 1835-1910, undated; 1 folder
    - Autograph letter, undated; 1 folder
      - 1 letter to "My dear Gilder", undated; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Udall, Nicholas, 1505-1556, 1545; 1 folder
    - indenture between John Ryther and Benjamin Gonson, acknowledging that Ryther had handed over 66 bills...including one bill of the playwright Nicholas Udall (signed by Ryther and William Staunford), 1545; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Vanbrugh, John, Sir, 1664-1726, 1704-1719; 1 folder
    - 3 letters 1707-1719: 2 to Peter Le Neve, 1 to Jacob Tonson, portion of 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - 1 letter by Peter Le Neve to Sir Thomas Wheat about Vanbrugh, 1704; portion of 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - 2 documents: 1 receipt for fees due to Robert Dale and John Vanbrugh, 1709 signed by Henry St. George Garret(?) ;1 warrant for John Grigsby to pay Thomas Rynaston the South Sea Company dividend of Charles Vanbrugh, 1712, portion of 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Victoria, Queen of Great Britain, 1819-1901, 1839; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    ALS, dated September 14 to 17, 1839, by young Queen Victora (signed “VR”), in German, to her cousin “Victo” (Victoire von Saxe-Coburg-Kohary, 1822-1857), telling her about the social life of Windsor Castle, 3 pp.
    Purchased in honor of Charles E. Greene upon his retirement.
  - Voltaire, 1694-1778, 1750-1779; 1 folder
    - Autograph letter to George Lyttleton, 1750; AMs, "A l'Impératrice de Russia", 1769; 4 MsS, contemporary copies of lettters and documents related to Voltaire, circa 1770s, 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Waley, Arthur, 1889-1966, undated; 2 folders
    - Autograph letters and manuscript, dates not examined; 1 folder
      - 3 letters ([1938?]-[1959]) to "Bunny" [David Garnett], undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - prose, "Hang P'eng" ("Chapter Three" crossed out), undated; 18 pp. (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Autograph letters to Robert Nichols, undated; 1 folder
      - 5 letters to Robert Nichols, undated; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Waller, Edmund, 1606-1687, 1651; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to John Evelyn, 1651; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Walpole, Horace, 1717-1797, 1759-1795; 2 folders
    - Autograph letters and manuscripts, 1759-1786; 1 folder
      - 5 letters 1759-1785: 1 to John Pinkerton, 1 to "Mr. Selwyn," 1 to Joseph Warton, 1 (in third person) to unidentified person, 1 to "Madam", portion of 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - verse, "Long had been lost...," 1764 22 lines, 1 p. (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - verse, "To her Royal Highness the Princess Amelia", 1786; 3 stanzas 1 pages (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Autograph letters, 1777-1795; 1 folder
      - 4 letters 1777-1795: 1 to Governor Thomas Pownall, 1 to Sir William Hamilton, 1 to George Augustus Selwyn, 1 (initialed) to unidentified person, 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Walsh, William, 1663-1708, 1703; 1 folder
    - Contains four copies in different hands of a poem by Walsh, "The Golden Age Retriev'd; or, the Fourth Eclogue of Virgil Translated," which was a Whig reply to the Tory poem "The Golden Age from the Fourth Eclogue of Virgil etc." Walsh's poem was later printed in Poems on Affairs of State, Vol. II 1703, p. 422, circa 1700, 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Watts, Isaac, 1674-1748, 1730-1904; 1 folder
    - 2 letters 1730-1746: 1 to Thomas Reader, 1 to unidentified person [Mrs. Stennet?] including 2 pages of textual changes/corrections for [her husband's?] poems, portion of 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Wayfarer's Love poetry anthology 1904: see Sutherland, Duchess of, portion of 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - White, Henry Kirke, 1785-1806, 1799-1803; 1 folder
    - 2 letters 1799-1803: 1 ("James Templeman") to R[ichard] Phillips, 1 to Vernor & Hood, 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Whitman, Walt, 1819-1892, 1865-1931 May 19; 4 folders
    - Whitman, Walt, 1819-1892, 1875-1931 May 19; 1 folder
      - 1 autograph statement concerning his illness; 1 letter to "Dear friend" [John Burroughs], 1882 1 note to R.M. Bucke, 1890; 3 photostats of letters petitioning for a government job for Whitman, 1875; 1 photostat of clipping from Washington Daily News, 1931 May 19;1 envelope addressed to Miss Mary Cabot; 1 label from a package addrssed to Mr. Ferguson (Whitman's printer), 1888, 1 item (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - 3 AMsS: "America," 1888 January 27; "As I Sit Writing Here," undated; "Going Somewhere," with three-line note for printers at the top, undated, 1 item (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Autograph letter to Anson Rider, 1865; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Autograph letters, 1867-1886; 1 folder
      - 13 letters 1867-1886: 11 to William M. Rossetti, 2 to Ernest Rhys, portion of 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 11)
      - prose, "Of Emersons 1st Vol ‘Nature’ ...," 2 pp. in pencil, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Leaves of Grass title page proof with holograph directions to the printer, undated; 1 p. (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Whittier, John Greenleaf, 1807-1892, 1828-1889; 1 folder
    - 30 letters circa 1828-1889 1 to Hon. H. [Carlson?]; 3 to Lydia Maria Child; 4 to James T. Fields; 1 to John Neal; 4 (signatures removed); 8 (and copies of 2 more letters) to Julia A. Hogdon; 1 to James Russell Lowell; 6 to Edward L. Pierce; 1 to "My Dear Frd [Friend]" 1 to unknown recipient; with photograph of Whittier, portion of 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - poem to Theodore D. Weld, 1838; portion of 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - poem in four lines, 1887; portion of 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - 2 signatures, 1871-1878>, portion of 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - verse, "Why climb the far off hills..." (in unidentified hand), 9 lines, 1 p., attributed to Whittier, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - verse, "‘Words butter no parsnips,’ the old adage says..." (in unidentified hand), 1 p., attributed to Whittier, undated; portion of 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Wilde, Oscar, 1854-1900, 1880-1899; 10 folders
    - Correspondence I, 1894; 1 folder
      - 4 letters undated 1 to "Miss Becker," 1 to "Miss Eale." 1 to "Miss Hardy," 1 to "Dear Gentlemen" [Elkin Matthews and John Lane? 1894], 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence II, 1882; 1 folder
      - 5 letters, 18821 to Mr. Allhuyen; 1 to Henry Ward Beecher; 1 to Charles Eliot Norton; 1 to Mr. Nutt; 1 to Mr. Ross, with photograph of Wilde, 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence III, 1893-1899; 1 folder
      - 3 letters 1893-1899: 2 to George Bernard Shaw, 1 to "Mr. Pigott", 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence IV, 1882-1892; 1 folder
      - 2 letters 1882-1892 1 to Theodore Tilton [1882], 1 to Herbert Beerbohm Tree 1892, 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Letters to Wilde, 1880-1894; 1 folder
      - 6 letters 1880-1894: 1 by Kyrle Bellew; 1 by Sir John Hare; 1 by Elken Mathews and John Lane, Publishers; 1 by Walter Pater, 1 by Herbert Beerbohm Tree, 1 by Lewis Waller, 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Epigrams ( undated 3 leaves), portion of 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Part of notebook containing epigrams and reflections by Wilde, undated 7 pp., portion of 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Financial, 1891-1898; portion of 1 folder
      - statement of draft collected from Lawrence Barrett, 1891; portion of 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 20)
      - "Final Return" for the 38th performance of The Importance of Being Earnest at the St. James Theatre, 1895; portion of 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 20)
      - list of expenses made out for Mr. Melmoth at Hotel De La Plage in Plage de Berneval-sur-Mer, 1897; portion of 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 20)
      - list of expenses made out for Mr. Melmoth at Hotel D'Alsace in Paris, 1898; portion of 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Photograph, undated; 1 folder
      - 1 photograph of Wilde, Mrs. W. Palmer, G. Meredith, and unidentified woman, signed by all, undated; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Fourteen Superb Autograph Letters... to Leonard Smithers, undated; 1 folder
      - 25 letters ([1897]-1899) to Leonard Smithers, his publisher, undated; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - The Duchess of Florence, 1882; portion of 2 folders
      - Autograph manuscript (5 leaves) of a portion of Act I, scene I from "The Duchess of Florentine," as submitted to Mary Anderson in 1882 and subsequently competed as "The Duchess of Padua," in 1883, undated; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 23)
      - 1 letter to My dear Steele", 1882; portion of 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Wilder, Thornton, 1897-1975, 1916-1942; 1 folder
    - Correspondence, 1916-1942; 1 folder
      - 11 letters 1916-1942: 2 to Harold B. Armitage, 6 to Rudolf Kommer, 2 to "Dear Norm," 1 to "Mr Lutoslawski", 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Williams, Edward E., 1821; 1 folder
    - Autograph letter to Edward Trelawney, 1821; 1 folder (Box 22, Folder 25)